Guide to the Paul Ehrlich Papers SC0223
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1994-007
  - Chapter by PRE & AHE in Health in a Changing World, ed. by Insel & Roth: (Box 5)
  - "Betw. Man & Environm.: Delicate Balance" (Box 5)
  - Untitled: We Almost Lost Detroit, John G. Fuller (Ehrlich citation) (Box 5)
  - Evolution Chapter Intro.: The Atlas of Planet Management. Myers (Box 5)
  - Book of Predictions (Box 6)
  - Intro. to Bug Bomb, Van den Bosch (Box 6)
  - Intro MARINE BIRDS AND MAMMALS OF PUGET SOUND by Tony Angell, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Intro to Thomson Book: REEF FISHES.... (Box 6)
  - (Foreward) Understanding the Environment, by Kenneth Watt. 1982 (Box 6)
  - The Strategy of Conservation. Ch. 19 in Conservation Biology. 1979 (Box 6)
  - Intro. to MAKE ROOM, MAKE ROOM by Harrison, 1972. (Box 6)
  - Intro. to Book by Gofman & Tamplin, 1970. (Box 6)
  - BLUEPRINT FOR SURVIVAL--Introduction. PRE 1972. (Box 6)
  - BLUEPRINT FOR SURVIVAL (Ecologist), Introduction. (Box 6)
  - Intro. to ZPG Science Fiction coll., ed. by Sauer, SHIP CALLED EARTH, 1970 (Box 6)
  - 1971 Introduction, Man and the Environment, Jackson (Box 6)
  - Introduction to ENVIRONMENTAL ADMINISTRATION by Edmunds-Letey, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Introduction to Man and the Environment, by Wesley Jackson (Box 6)
  - Campus Report, 8/79 (Box 6)
  - Campus Report--Summer '79 (Box 6)
  - Cape Cod Times--7/31/80 (Box 6)
  - Christian Science Monitor (Box 6)
  - Current Biography (Box 6)
  - Dallas Morning News--1974 (Box 6)
  - Dictionary of International Biography (Box 6)
  - Elle 1972 (Box 6)
  - Fortune, 1979 (Box 6)
  - Friends of the Earth, interview 9/77 (Box 6)
  - Human Behavior, May 1975 (Box 6)
  - New York Times (Box 6)
  - Hearst op-ed. September 1973 (Box 6)
  - Kansas City Star (Box 6)
  - LA Times: Sept. 8, 1974 (Box 7)
  - London Times--Feb. 1972, June 1972 (Box 7)
  - London Times (Box 7)
  - Le Monde: (same as London Times article, May 1972) (Box 7)
  - National Enquirer (Box 7)
  - A Dark Age Threat. San Francisco Examiner. Sept. 12, 1973 (Box 7)
  - SF Examiner (Box 7)
  - Wall Street Journal 8/27/70 (Box 7)
  - Stanford (Box 7)
  - Untitled: Am. Phys. Soc. Press release: April, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Associated Press--NY (Box 7)
  - AUFBAU--Profile of the Week, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Australian Newspapers Service, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Bay News 1/78 PRE "Why I wrote the book" (Race Bomb) (Box 7)
  - Bioscience--1975 (Box 7)
  - CALIFORNIA LIVING Interview 1978 (Box 7)
  - 1982 Darlington, David: THE MAN WHO MADE BABIES DISAPPEAR. Cal Today (Box 7)
  - Hearst Papers (Box 7)
  - Kansas Alumni--interview '81--'82 (Box 7)
  - LIFE (Box 7)
  - Liveoak (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles Times (Box 7)
  - Mother Earth News: Interview 1974 (Box 7)
  - Media & Methods: PRE Interview 9/75 (Box 7)
  - New Scientist--1971 (Box 7)
  - Newsday (Box 7)
  - Newsweek (Box 7)
  - NOT MAN APART--Books Hall of fame, PRE list (Box 7)
  - NOT MAN APART (Ecoscience)--Interview, book review 1977 (Box 7)
  - LA ONDA (Stfd): Interview 1979 (Box 7)
  - The Observer (London) (Box 7)
  - Pacific Press--interview with Max Philops--1968? (Box 7)
  - Peninsula Magazine--Interview 1/77--78 (Box 8)
  - Palo Alto Times (Box 8)
  - The Science (Rae Goodell) 1977 (Box 8)
  - Stanford Observer (Box 8)
  - San Diego Union (Box 8)
  - SF Chronicle (Box 8)
  - San Jose Mercury (Box 8)
  - Herb Caen (Box 8)
  - Sylvia Porter Column (Box 8)
  - Dick Gregory (Box 8)
  - Art Hoppe (Box 8)
  - Charles McCabe (Box 8)
  - Stanford West African Relief Famine Fund--Sp. 1974 (Box 8)
  - TEXAS Newspapers & others, Forum in 1967 (Box 8)
  - TIME (Box 8)
  - Wall Street Journal (Box 8)
  - Washington Post (Box 8)
  - Newspapers--General (Box 8)
  - SJ Mercury News 4/78 Interview (Box 8)
  - San Francisco Examiner (Box 8)
  - San Jose Mercury (Box 8)
  - South China Morning Post (Hong Kong) (Box 8)
  - Stanford Press Releases--Extra Copies 1970 (Box 8)
  - Special Reports, Inc. Special Reports--Ecology (Box 8)
  - Stanford Daily (Box 8)
  - Stanford Observer (Box 8)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1996-146
  - KNAW Heineken Lectures, 1998 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1997-228
  - The Mother Earth Handbook (includes article "Population Control: Necessary but Insufficient," by Paul and Anne Ehrlich), 1991 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2000-296
  Scope and Contents note
  This accession contains mostly clippings, magazine articles, newsletters, and press releases regarding Anne and Paul Ehrlich's work, with some correspondence and a few photographs.
  - 1948-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1961 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1963 Photos of Paul Ehrlich and Susan Davidson (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1967 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1968 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1969 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1970 (2) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1970 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1970 newsprint (2) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1971 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1972 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1973 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1974 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1975 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1976 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 1977 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1978 newsprint (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Articles 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Articles 1972-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photos (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Population Biology Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Press Releases and Misc. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Zero Pop. Growth and assorted misc. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - One-Dimensional Ecology (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Taking Sides: Clashing Views on Controversial Environmental Issues (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Almanac of the Environment: The ecology of everyday life (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2001-202
  - Field notes, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ISCOL Lecture brochure, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Larvae – internal (copies) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Species – locality sheets – Colorado (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Internal - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Grids (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lupine studies - illustrations (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Larvae – external (copies) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Larvae – internal (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Genitalia – plates (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Genitalia – dissection survey (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Natrix problem (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Drosophila Project (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - List of butterflies dissected, Sept. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Magdalena Epipsodia (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wichita State University lecture, clippings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Analysis for dist. & subsp. Of E. Epipsodia (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Genitalia – characters and data (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - USAF project, 1956-57 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Instructions for preserving adult butterflies in fluid (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "The Relative Effects of Genetic Drift and Natural Selection in Small Populations, with Special Reference to the Work on Cepaea" (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - MacFarlandi (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Papilionid Project (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Species experiment (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Skipper drawings (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gut – drawings (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Butterfly dissection data (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Monarch – internal (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Monarch – internal (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Heads – drawings (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Thorax – plates (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Legs – drawings (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Genitalia – Hesperiidae (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Genitalia – unidentified (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Heads – drawings (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Rohlf factor plots (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dendrograms – internal, external (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Butterfly – external (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Internal – External (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Thorax data (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Internal – leg, gut & genital (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - External (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Internal – External (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Internal correlation (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - PRE (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "The Phenetic Relationships of the Butterflies. I. Adult Taxonomy and the Nonspecificity Hypothesis," 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Internal – summary (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Phenetic Relationships of Adult Butterflies (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Butterfly – plant (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Butterfly plant (letters checked) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Plant butterfly final (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Butterfly plant [lists, typescript of papers] (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Butterfly plant [lists] (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Records: butterfly – food plant relationships (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Photographs of butterflies (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Note cards (Box 2)
  - Publications (Box 2)
  - Poster from lecture at Stony Brook (Box 2)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2003-052
  - Two Italian translations of Ehrlich books: Per Salvare Il Pianeta [Healing the Planet]. Franco Muzzio Editore 1992 Un Pianeta non Basta [The Population Explosion]. Franco Muzzio Editore 1991 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2003-076
  - Correspondence, 1981-89 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990-93 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1994-97 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anne Ehrlich – bio (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Earth – TV series (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "For our Children’s Sake" – KQED TV essay (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Paul Ehrlich and the Bomb – TV program (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Heinz Family Foundation and award to Ehrlichs (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mitchell prize (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Nuclear Age Peace Foundation (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Velsicol v. Ehrlich (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Getting the Prices Right; a report based on the proceedings of the first annual Wirth Chair Conference on the Report of the President’s Council on Sustainability Denver, Colorado, 1997 [no Ehrlich articles] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Betrayal of Science and Reason – reviews (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Betrayal of Science and Reason – reviews (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Birder's Handbook – reviews (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cassandra Conference - reviews (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Cold and the Dark - reviews (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Earth - reviews (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ecoscience - reviews (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Extinction - reviews (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Extinction - reviews (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Golden Door – reviews (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Healing the Planet – reviews (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Human Natures – reviews (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Machinery of Nature - reviews (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - New World, New Mind – reviews (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Population Explosion – reviews (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Race Bomb - reviews (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Reviews, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ehrlich, Paul "A Preliminary Survey of the Male Genitalia of the Butterflies (Lepidoptera: Papilionoidea)" (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ehrlich, Paul "A Preliminary Survey of the Male Genitalia of the Butterflies (Lepidoptera: Papilionoidea)" (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Thesis drawings (original) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ehrlich, Paul "The Morphology, Phylogeny and Higher Classification of the Butterflies (Lepidoptera: Papilionoidea)," Ph.D. dissertation, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book reviews - AHE (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AHE articles (1 of 6) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AHE articles (2 of 6) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - AHE articles (3 of 6) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - AHE articles (4 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - AHE articles (5 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - AHE articles (6 of 6) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ecofables/Ecoscience, Vol. 1, 1997-98 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ecology – Ehrlich group publications (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Missing Connections," Ehrlich et. al., 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mother Earth columns, 1982-86 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1970-73 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1974-77 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1978-79 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1991: A - I (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1991: P – V (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - PHE & AHE writings, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - PHE & AHE writings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Articles citing PRE & AHE (1 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Articles citing PRE & AHE (2 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Articles citing PRE & AHE (3 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Articles citing PRE & AHE (4 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Publicity - AHE (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - News release - PRE (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - PRE – newspaper articles (1 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - PRE – newspaper articles (2 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - PRE – newspaper articles (3 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - PRE – newspaper articles (4 of 4) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1990 Jan.-June (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1990 July-Dec. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Press on the Ehrlichs, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: dist. from literature (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: gut morphology (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: gut contents (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: feeding, raw data (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: stomach contents (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: distrib and feeding summaries (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes for butterfly fish research: mouth parts (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2004-149
  - American Institute of Biological Science, Conclave of Presidents, program materials, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Conservation Biology and Biodiversity, a series of public lectures sponsored by the Department of Zoology, The University of Tennessee Knoxville (includes page on Anne Ehrlich), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Holdren, John P. "A Brief History of 'IPAT' (impact = population x affluence x technology)", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - PRE speaking schedule, 1970-71 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Today Show – scripts, 1989-91 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Society for Conservation Biology Newsletter, Feb. 2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Waddell, Craig, "Perils of a Modern Cassandra," typescript drafts with related correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report on Nature article by Ehrlich and others from Stanford Report, Jan. 15, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of Ehrlich books (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ehrlich writings, 1967-71 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ehrlich writings, 1992-99 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ehrlich writings, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ehrlich writings, typescripts, 1967-97 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Press on Ehrlichs, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Australian Conservation Foundation "The World's Park,", 1989; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2005-170
  - National Association of Biology Teachers 1992 Distinguished Service Award for Paul Ehrlich (Box 1)
  - Paul Ehrlich’s Doctor of Science Degree from Oregon State University (June 13, 1999) (Box 1)
  - The Consequences of Nuclear War (July 11 and 12, 1984) (Box 1)
  - Directory (Matrikel) of the Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences 1991 (Box 1)
  - Anne Ehrlich’s Doctor of Science Degree from Oregon State (June 13, 1999) (Box 1)
  - 1998 Tyler Prize Media Report (Box 1)
  - Certificate of Appreciation for Anne Ehrlich from the Pacific Institute (Oct. 18, 1997) (Box 1)
  - Heinekenprijzen 1998 (Box 1)
  - The Dr. H.P. Heineken and Dr. A. H. Heineken Prizes 1998, w/ photos in envelope (Box 1)
  - Volvo Environment Prize (Box 1)
  - Akademie Nieuws 1998 (Box 1)
  - Blue Planet Prize 1999 (Box 1)
  - Staord News Press releases (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Africa (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Butterfly seminar (Dec. 8, 1978) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Race Seminar (Oct. 1977) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Next Carson--The Tonight Show (Feb. 8, 1979) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Carson Show (Nov. 1, 1979 and May 26, 1981) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Orient Lectures 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Shipboard Lectures SA 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Radio and TV Shows: Book tour itinerary for The Golden Door (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Human Biology Lecture Notes (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Population Lectures 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biology 150 Lecture Notes (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Biology 150—notes on coevolution (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Population Biology Lecture #10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Entomology Notes (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Seminars (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Generation of Diversity and Race (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bio and Social Responsibility (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Biology 10 Lecture (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Biology 150 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Population Biology Master 1966 Duplicate (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Biology 10 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Biology 10 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Biology 10 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Graduate Core (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Coevolution Course (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Euphy Seminar (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - U.C. Santa Barbara January 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - P-H Coevolution Lecture (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ehrlich Press Releases Nuclear War (return to complete set) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ehrlich Press Releases 1975- (#65) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ehrlich Press Releases 1959-1974 (#1-64) and Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Press Releases 2000- (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Econews #419; "Conversations on Population—Dr. Paul Ehrlich" Part II; 30:09; Mono c. 1987; Educational Communications, Inc., 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Blue Planet Prize 1999; Opening slide show/Profile slide show, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Blue Planet Prize 1999; Press Coerence/Commemorative Lectures (Box 2)
  - The Climate Report; Update On Global Warming; Sierra Club; (loose iormation inside), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Blue Planet Prize 1999; Awards Ceremony and Congratulatory Party (Box 2)
  - BBC A103: TV28 "The Copulation Explosion"; Producer: Amanda Willett; (loose iormation inside), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Life of the Mind; Human Natures: Genes vs. Cultures (Ehrlich); The Staord Channel, 37023; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Public Interest Video Network; "The World After Nuclear War"; 30:00, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - "Sundance"? 1989, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Roger Bingham Host/Producer; "The Time of Our Lives", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - "A Finite World"; Global population problems and solutions; Barbara Pyle, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - TDA - 2-15, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - "Earth"; Prog 2; Order 85237; VHS 525 NTSC; Cutting Copy as of 6-12-86, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Paul Ehrlich; "Segments", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Sightings-Show #4-039; Edited Master; TRT – 45:13, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - "The Doomsayers"; (AHE) 1981, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Hearst Programs, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Paul Ehrlich; "Segments"; "Today" Show 1990, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Sunday Morning News; "Trouble In Air"; 7/10/88, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - United Nations Population Fund; "Changing Nature: Population and Environment at a Crossroads"; US Committee Version with wEb End Slate, 10/03/01; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - "Earth" Prog 1; Parts 1-2; VHS 525 NTSC; 13/11/86, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - National Audubon Society; "What is The Limit?", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - KQED; "Paul Ehrlich and The Population Bomb"; A Production of KQED/Buffalo Gap Productions, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Econews #422; "Conversations on population—Ann Ehrlich"; c. 1988; length: 29:28, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - Southern California Population Crisis Committee; "Dr. Paul H. Ehrlich Speaking at UCLA" 9-25-1988; "Back to the Future of Planet Earth", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Coerence on World after Nuclear War", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Questions for PRE" 7+8; "Coerence on World after Nuclear War", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Last"; "Coerence on World after Nuclear War", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Coerence on World after Nuclear War"; 1+2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Coerence on World after Nuclear War"; "side 1+2"; "Panels", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Coerence on World after Nuclear War"; "2-5+6"; "Moscow Link", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - NPR’s "Talk of the Nation"; "Science Friday"; 12/27/96; "Environmental Update", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Desert Island Disc"; Paul Ehrlich (with R. Williams) December 1994; ABC Radio Australia, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Anne Ehrlich; (CIF presentation), 4/28/80; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - unlabeled, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Allegro,", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Dr. Paul Ehrlich; Intro 3:00, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Cousteau Society Involvement Day; (loose iormation sheet inside), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "It’s A Matter Of Survival" Program 2; Canadian Broadcasting Corporation; D-0347, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "It’s A Matter Of Survival" Program 5; Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Carson Show", 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Environment Show #322"; 3/3/96, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - unlabeled, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - AHE on KQED "Forum"; Sierra Club on Immigration 11-97, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - "Conversations with The Christian Science Monitor" March 19 1986, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
  - Paul Ehrlich; "The Future of the Environment and the future of Environmental Science"; Staord Video, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - "Think Tank"; with Ben Wattenberg; TTBW 12114; "How Should Humanity Prosper?"; Guest: Paul Ehrlich; PBS Air Date 5/13/2004; Copyright New River Media Inc., 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - Global Coerence 2003; "The Long View: Is History Destiny?"; TRT: 87 min.; 31 – March – 03; (loose iormation sheet attached), 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - "Up Close With Patsy Smullin"; "Dr. Paul Ehrlich"; 28:56; copyright 1999 COBI, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)
  - PRF + Pop Bomb, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 3)